So the first thing we need to do is actually define a metric, or
因此我们要做的第一件事是为我们的实验定义一个
maybe multiple metrics, for our experiment.
或多个指标
In other words, we need to decide how we're going to measure whether
也就是说 我们需要确定如何衡量
the experiment group is better than the control group or not.
实验组比对照组好还是差
Carrie, how do you get started with this?
Carrie 你会如何开始？
>> Well, the first thing you want to do is think about what you're going to use
你要做的第一件事是在决定如何定义这些指标之前
the metrics for, before you decide how you're going to define them.
先想一想你会用这些指标来做什么
>> Right, and
是的
so, if you're thinking about how you're going to use the metric,
如果想想如何使用这些指标
there are really two main use cases.
实际上有两个主要的使用案例
The first is what we call invariant checking, and these
第一个是 我们称为不变量检查
are the metrics that shouldn't change across your experiment and your control.
这些指标在实验组和对照组中都不会更改
For example, if you're running an experiment and
例如 如果运行一个实验组和一个对照组
a control, one major term of comparison is, are the populations the same?
进行对比的一个主要的项目是总体是否相同
So you might check one, do you have the same number of users across the two?
因此 你可能会检查这两组中用户数量是否相同
The other thing that you might check is, is the distribution the same?
你可能检查的另一项是分布是否相同
So, do you have comparable numbers of users across countries, or by language?
你是否具有可比较的各个国家的用户数量 或各个语言的用户数量呢？
All of these things are sanity checked to make sure that your experiment is
需要进行这些完整性检查 确保实验能够
actually run properly.
顺利实施
The second use case is going to be evaluation,
第二个使用案例是评估
which is basically what Carrie talked about in the first place.
Carrie 一开始基本上已经谈到了
>> And even for evaluation,
对于评估
you're going to have a couple of different things to think about.
你需要考虑很多不同的东西
First, you have what you think of as high level business metrics, so
首先 是你认为属于高级业务指标的那些
that might be how much revenue you make, what your market share is,
可能是你获得多少收益 市场份额是多少
how many users you have.
拥有多少用户
And then you're going to want more detailed metrics that focus on, say,
接下来 你需要更详细的指标
the user experience with actually using your product,
如产品的用户体验
how long they stay on your page, things like that.
他们在你的网页停留多长时间等
>> Okay. Can you give some examples of when you'd
好 你能举一些例子
need these more detailed metrics?
说明什么时候需要这些更详细的指标吗？
>> Sure.
当然可以
So, let's say for example that you have a particular user experience.
比如说 你有特殊的用户体验
One example is maybe users aren't finishing a class, on audacity.
用户没能在 Audacity 完成一节课
Well, we don't know why, but we,
我们不知道原因是什么
what we want to do is we want to dig in to the user experience for that class.
但我们想要做的是挖掘用户对那节课的用户体验
Maybe the videos are taking too long to load, and we should look at latency.
可能这些视频太长了 我们应该看看延迟问题
Maybe some of the quizzes are particularly difficult, and
也许有些测试题太难了
the students are having trouble with that.
学生做起来有困难
Right? And so
那么
what we want is we want a set of techniques to help us really dig
我们需要一套技术帮我们挖掘
into that user experience.
这个用户体验
And so we'll talk about a bunch of these methods.
我们这里会讨论一系列方法
One of them is going to be user experience research,
其中一个方法是用户体验研究
which we can use in order to brainstorm metrics.
我们可以通过该方法 对指标进行头脑风暴
>> And sometimes your business metrics may just not work out in
有时 在实验中 你的业务指标
the context of any experiment.
可能无法使用
So for you may not have the information you need, or the time that you're
你可能没有得到需要的信息
running the experiment may be too short to measure what you want.
或者你运行实验的时间太短 不能测量到你想要的信息
If we think about our online courses, maybe what we're really interested
在我们的在线课程案例中
in is whether students get more jobs after taking the class, or
我们可能想知道学习课程之后 学生是否能够得到更多工作
something more nebulous like did they have improved skills.
或是否能够提升自身技能
Now the problem with the jobs one is we just don't have complete information.
现在关于工作的问题是我们没有完整的信息
We could try serving students, but we'll never really know if they got a job as
我们可以尝试为学生服务 但实际上我们不知道他们
a result of this class except maybe over a very long period of time.
是否由于学习了本课程找到了工作 当然过了很长时间的情况除外
And then we also don't have time, right?
我们也没有时间
We're running an experiment right now, and even if we could prove that someone
我们现在马上进行一个实验 即使我们能够证明
got a job as a result of this, we wouldn't necessarily get that
有些学生由于学习了本课程找到了工作 我们不一定
information within a month, they might get a job six months later.
能够在一个月之内得到这个信息 他们可能会在六个月之后找到工作
And then there's the category of things which are more nebulous,
有些事情就更加模糊了
like improved skills.
如技能提升
How do we really measure that in an experiment?
我们如何在实验中衡量这些事情呢？